Alieu Gilbert Fullah

Address: New Site Devil Hole, Waterloo High-Way, Freetown,

Sierra Leone, 00232 Phone: +23234727215

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/qilbert-

<u>fullah-</u>6601873b E-mail:

gilbertfullah@hotmail.com

Network and System Administrator with over 4 years of successful experience in networking and system administration at Bollore Transport and Logistics Freetown Sierra Leone. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in the network infrastructure of Bollore Transport and Logistics. Also, more than 3 months of experience at Wicresoft Shanghai China branch as a Technical Support Engineer for the Microsoft Teams product. I recently joined UNDP Smart Infrastructure and Connectivity Unit in Copenhagen Denmark as ICT Support Engineer.

Skills

Python, SQL, Tableau, Excel, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, configuration, troubleshooting and deployment of Cisco networking devices, Windows Servers, Web Scraping, GIT, HTML, CSS3

Work History

2014-06 - 2018-08

Network Administrator

Bollore Transport and Logistics, Freetown Sierra Leone

- Monitoring the overall company network system in Sierra Leone.
- Configuring routers, switches, PCs used daily by the organization.
- PC maintenance and PC assistant for users at the company.
- Administering the Servers and Configuring the Active Directory system used at the company.
- System administrator, administering the overall system of the company.

2020-08 - 2021-06 **Technical Support Engineer**

Wicresoft Shanghai China Branch

- Troubleshooting customer problems relating to Microsoft Teams.
- Solving customer problems relating to Microsoft Teams.
- Prepare accurate and timely reports.

2021-07 - 2021-12

ICT Support Engineer

UNDP (SICU) Unit, Copenhagen Denmark

- Solving network and connectivity problems around UNDP offices around the world.
- Working on IoT devices such as smart healthcare project were I gather data from the sensors, analyze, visualize and do prediction to help better optimize the use of IoT deployment on UNDP offices and countries.

2021-07 - 2022-05

Lecturer II

University of Lunsar, Lunsar, Sierra Leone.

- Conducting lectures on ICT for students in the Nursing and Engineering departments.
- Develop, architect and implement the network infrastructure of the University of Lunsar.
- University of Lunsar Information Technology administrator for network, learning platform and medical center.

2022-06 - Present

Data Analyst

Institute for Governance Reform (IGR), Freetown, Sierra Leone

- Data Monitoring, cleaning and analysis.
- Collaborate with IGR staffs on different programs relating to data.

Education

2018-09 - 2020-08

Master of Science: Information and Communication Engineering

Huazhong University of Science and Technology - Wuhan, Hubei, China

2009-10 - 2013-07 Bachelor of Science: Information Systems

University of Sierra Leone - Freetown, Sierra Leone

Coursework

Python Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Data Structures, Data Mining, Machine Learning, Research on Natural Language Processing, Internet of Things, E-commerce, Network Security and Project Management.

Projects

- Topic and Sentiment Analysis on Belt and Road Initiative Using News Articles in Kenya and China Media.
- Smart Healthcare System in Uganda using IoT devices.